Vose Galleries of Boston
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Art-Related Files, circa 1876, 1890s-1947, Series 3:; (Box 24; 7 folders)
  This series is compiled of miscellaneous materials related to artists including newspaper and magazine clippings, biographies, signatures, and scattered notes. Also found is a handwritten manuscript regarding the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia, PA, and a videocassette of "Tales of an Art Dealer" about the Vose Galleries and its founding family produced by Vose Galleries of Boston in 1991.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Artists' Biographies, circa 1890s-1920s (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Coppenwrath, undated (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Lukits, Theodore N., circa 1900s-1947 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Manuscript, Art Exhibit at the Centennial Exhibition (1876, Philadelphia, PA) [unknown author], circa 1876 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Materials, 1928, 1937, undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Mostyn, Tom, circa 1900s-1920s (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Signatures, 1919, undated (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - "Tales of an Art Dealer," Vose Galleries of Boston Recording, circa 1991, (1 videocassette, 28 min.) (Box 24, Folder 36)
- Financial Records, 1911-1962, 1991, Series 4:; (Boxes 24-25; 1.8 linear feet)
  Records relating to sales, consignments, framing and restoration, banking, and other financial business operations are found here. Materials include invoices, receipts, statements, scattered correspondence, handwritten and typed notes, and some price lists. The bulk of the records range from the late 1940s-early 1960s.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by account name or subject.
  - A File, 1950, 1954, 1961-1962 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Accounts [Misc. Receipts, Notes and Correspondence], 1949, 1953-1962, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 38-39)
  - Thos. Agnew & Sons, 1924-1934, 1949-1962 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - B File, circa 1949-1955 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Babcock Galleries, 1924-1959 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - A.M. Bouwens, 1941-1950, 1958-1960 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - The F.H. Bresler Co., 1925-1930, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - C File, 1948, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Campbell, Robert, 1945-1946, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - George Chapellier Gallery, 1944-1946 (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - Childs, Charles D., 1944, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - D File, 1950-1959 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - E File, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - F File, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - The Fine Art Society, 1951-1956 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - French Gallery, 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Frost & Reed, 1950-1962, (3 folders) (Box 24, Folder 54-56)
  - G File, 1947-1962 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Clapp & Graham Co., Inc., 1924-1958 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1927-1944 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - H File, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Hanna, John, 1936-1939 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Heiman, J.M., 1941 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Hirschl, Norman [Hirschl & Adler Galleries], 1941, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Ireland, Leroy, 1911, 1941-1955, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Kennedy & Co., 1924-1961 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - F. Kleinberger Galleries, 1922-1961 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Klimann, Gustav, 1955-1962 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - M. Knoedler & Co., 1922-1957, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
  - Kraushaar, C.W., circa 1945-1955 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - L File, 1942-1959 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - J. Leger & Son, Inc., 1927-1934 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - M File, 1947-1954 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Milch Galleries, 1937-1960 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - N File [Primarily National Shawmut Bank], 1943-1962, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - Newhouse Galleries, 1929-1948, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Newton, Arthur U., 1928-1947 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Nicholson, John, 1936-1962, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 23-24)
  - Norton Galleries [Includes Gertrude M. Norton], 1923-1955 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - O-R File, 1915-1960 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - S File, 1925-1958 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Schaeffer Galleries, 1937-1951 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - The Schneider-Gabriel Galleries, 1941-1948 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Henry Schultheis Co., 1915-1935 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Schwab, E.H., 1942 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Scott & Fowles, 1915-1953 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - W. Scott & Sons, 1915-1937 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Stone, Harry, 1933-1949 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - [T-Z File?], 1923, 1946-1962 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Tax Blanks [Miscellaneous Materials], circa 1961 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Travel, circa 1957-1960 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - U.S. Printing & Lithograph Co., 1928-1934 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Walker Galleries, 1952-1953 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Wallis & Son, 1917-1930 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Wildenstein & Co., 1912, 1925-1953 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Williams & Sutch, 1922-1930 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - E. J. van Wisselingh & Co., 1953-1954 (Box 26 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Worksheets for Financial Statements, 1961 (Box 26 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Howard Young Galleries, 1923-1941, (2 folders) (Box 26 (hol), Folder 3-4)
- Printed Materials, circa 1904-1990, Series 5:; (Boxes 26-27; 0.4 linear feet)
  Printed Materials contains intermixed exhibition catalogs from Vose Galleries and other galleries; Vose Galleries postcards and Christmas cards; booklets about artists; and fragile newspaper clippings. Some exhibition catalogs have notations written on them. The bulk of the material is from the early 1900s-1950s.
  - Advertising, 1926-1928, 1934, undated (Box 26 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Data on Southern Trip, circa 1933, (Fragile materials) (Box 26 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Cards and Booklets, circa 1904-1990, (4 folders) (Box 26 (hol), Folder 7-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Cards and Booklets, circa 1904-1990, (2 folders) (Box 27 (pam), Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1944-1946 (Box 27 (pam), Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1911-1948, (2 folders; Fragile materials) (Box 27 (pam), Folder 4-5)
  - Various Printed Materials Arranged Alphabetically, circa 1914-1933 (Box 27 (pam), Folder 6)